<topics>
  <topic>
    <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-april-fools</id>
    <results>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85034039/1871-04-21/ed-1/?sp=1&amp;q=april+fools+pranks</id>
        <rel>0</rel>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84026994/1873-04-01/ed-1/?sp=2&amp;q=april+pranks+fools</id>
        <rel>0</rel>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn82014635/1894-04-01/ed-1/?sp=11&amp;q=april+fools+pranks</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>T like to April fool our manager, perhaps,
but we don't April fool ourse'ves, be
cause that would be rather cruel.
I have outgrown the frolicsomenes
of April 1, of course; still I always look
carefully after my coat tails on that
day. And I greatly enjoy the motley
of those who are careless about their
parraental caudals during the Feast of
All Fools. The sight makes me feel
quite a boy again, for we youngsters
used to do that sort of thing in Phila
delphia thirty years ago. 0 yes, I did
It, too. I believe that some of the live
lier children of Philadelphia do it yet,
and have vitality and energy enough
left to laugh at the result, as a comio
paragrapher would say.
The most foolhardy of all the tricks
which I can recall in connection with
this carnival of jeering and nonsense
Is one that I have never seen played
Eince I was old enough to require two
digits to express my age. A bag and
two boys were the ingredients of the
trick, and it never failed to 6core a
great success on a quiet side street.
One boy got into the bag and the other
Stood by it waiting for the victim. The
rest of the boys who were "in on the
ground floor" were hiding in hallways
and doors and behind trucks across
the street. An innocent citizen came
W sauntering along. The boy who had
hold of the neck of the bag stopped
him with a "Say, mister, please give
toe a lift, will yer?" The innocent cit
izen usually acquiesced and took hold
of the bag to land it on the youngster's
shoulder. Just as he got it fairly in
his hands the boy in the bag suddenly
kicked and screamed. Innocent vic
tim, thinking it a bagful of wildcats
or hypnas. let go quickly and ran off
with palpitating heart and hair on end.
while all the boys across the street
pursued him with a villainous chorus
of "April fool 1 April fool! Wash
.your face and go to sclioU" or
something to the same effect. It
Talways seemed to me that the joke
was really on the boy in the bag;
he was sometimes dropped hastily
and heavily and was hurtand occa
sionally the April-fooled citizen gave
him a thrashing besides for being too
funny. But it was an effective trick.
and often an old codger lingered in the
shadow on the opposite pavement to
witness and enjoy the sport. You have
seen a man try to kick a plug hat full
of pig iron over into tho next state
Trell, bis discomfiture was no greater
IT MADE AIM SMD.E.
Good Ola reliOK Ali, hoT it warms ri7
bcart to see them playing their littlo inuoccm
tricks on the Brst or Apnlt Used to do It my
self when I was a toy. But ibey caa't fool me,
though I'm too oU a bird lor fiat.
than that of the man whoso blood was
frozen in his heart by the unexpected
scream emitted by the occupant of the
bag. Laugh? It would make a tomb
stone roll over in a fit of hysterics.
Jonx Drew.
fOMETIlIES IT GIVES PLEASURE TO OTHERS.
It doesn't seem right that the firs
flay of a month so full of pretty things
j is April is should be inseparably con
w nectcd in our minds with empty ard
dilapidated pocketbooks with string
in d-small-boy attachments, di&rep
ntable hats with bricks underneath
them, long streamers hanging from
l nnsuspecting coattails, door bells
rung by invisible hands, and all the
other dear old pleasantries that we
know by heart. And we should prob.
ibly have had a society for the pre
rention of Anril fool iokes Ions aso if
It were not for the pleasure that call
aren gel out of them.
When a certain boy of my acquaint-
fcnee on April Grst. before breakfast,
Informs me that somebody is waiting
ft;' see me in the library, not for the
world would I refuse to go downstairs
and pretend extreme surprise at find
ing nobody there. Nor would any
thing induce me to decline the suspicious-looking,
cotton-filled piece of
candy which is shortly after offered
V.T. a fmnll rrirl I know. I bitA
UlUiD O
End- Hotter SS6? itLISSrularly i
every year, ana Mr. rfat Gooxnvm or
Mr. Francis Wilson would be glad if
he could raise such a shout of laughter
as easily and unfailingly.
Apropos of this train of thought
there is a little picture of mine in Puck,
published some years since, which will
perhaps bear transplanting here, and
which I subjoin.
Fbedeiuck Buitn Oppeb.
"de bazoo" is suggested.
If yer want a good joke on some ot
yer frcn's, give dem de razoo, see?
Dat's de way dey do in Xew York oa
April Fool day.Den yer kin pay off all yer old
grudges de same way. Or if yer hun-
gry and ain't got no money walk inter
de restrint, see, and eat all yer kin,
and say it's April Fool, see, and run
out widout payin' nothin'.
Dat's de racket fer April Fool de
razoo. Steve Erodie.
TO LESSEN THE DEVTL'S FOOLS.
I am abked for a sentiment concern
ing April Fool's day and pause in the
whirl and rush of a righteous warfare
to say that in my opinion time is far
too valuable and important a factor
for a moment to be lost in foolish jest
ing or senseless joking. The world,
especially in these days, is in far too
critical and dangerous a position, so
cially and religiously, to allow of a
man with average sense to saj' noth
ing of those who have consecrated
brains to indulge in any other than
profitable and upright intercourse.
It is a personal relief to me to feel
that in our ranks seventeen hundred
officers and sixteen thousand unpaid
local workers will be pushing with
might and main of soul an enterprise
which upholds sincerity and the ne
cessity of lessening the devil's fools.
Ballington Booth.
A CHA3IPI0X FOR THE DAT.
Before stating what jokes seem to
me timely, and enjc&abJe ior this
S&-
WIPE DE FLOOB WID niil."
April Fool's day, I cannot resist th
temptation to say that I think the
spirit of the holiday itself hat always
been singularly misunderstocd. The
day is really to be deemed a pause in
time's serious flight, when folly could
with propriety travesty wisdom, and
set the world smiling. As it is, the
first of April has come to be deemed a
nuisance, wheu its observance is not
don away with entirely. April Fool's
day is sadly in need of soue one to
champion it and xestoi e it to its right
ful place in the calendar. It is not
simply the day on which the boys and
girls may make fools of their elders
with impunity. I suspect that there
was a time when it was regarded
rightly, far away as that time seems
to us now. Then the old people put
aside their serious looks and grew
younger instead of older.
If it takes a wise man to be a fool,
surely April first is the feast day
of the saircs. when thev can act on
Shakcspsare's admonition: "Mingle a
little folly with your wisdom."
As for those jokes which seem to mi
good and appropriate to the dav it
should always be understood that the
element of surprise is the essential
thing. Novelty is wit. Jokes must not
bo cruel pranks, otherwise the day
would ba given up to a general hazing
of everybody. The most successful of
April Fool jokes would be to surprise
one's friends by a change of character.
What a rare joke it would be for the
confirmed miser to bestow a dowry
upon that niece of his who needs only
a little money to marry the lad of her
choice. If all the cranks would put
rside their hobbies for a day, what fun
it would be for the rest of us.
This kind of joke can be carried out
ad finitum and would never fail to bo
successful. Let the tippler remain
sober to-day just as a joke. The skin
flint employer can have a lark with
his clerk by granting that increase of
salary that has been talked about so
long. Let the clergyman I say it
reverently preach a sermon only an
hour long to-day instead of one of
four hours' duration. I am convinced
that the idea would meet with success.
People too old for jokes on April
Fool's day? Xouscnc. Even the gray
heads can have their joke. The repro
bate roue can go to church this morn
ing and explain that it is all a joke on
his part. Many a man is ashamed to do
a good thing because it is so unusual
with him that it would give him un
pleasant prominence. But he can do
it to-day and escape with the admis
sion that it is his April fool joke. I
am glad the day comes on Sunday this
year.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84024442/1896-03-29/ed-1/?sp=17&amp;q=april+fools+pranks</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>These hlMorl
calcaes are not
ed by way of pre
lude to i he slate
ment rhat April
Fools' Day Is
again with us, or
will be on "Wed
nesday next. Af
ter these i-ad ex
amples of mind
read mg, it will
be only t tie more
perplexing to
discover the dif
ference between
looking the gift
horse !u the
mouth and the
gift horse him
self should lie
gallop up to the
door.
One half of the
world will begin
on "Wednesday to,
play pranks on
Uie other half,
and it is an in
teresting day be
cause we have
only two such
days on Uie cal
endar, the other
being Talentine
Day. Election
day Miotild. per
haps, be added,
buttoallofthem
FaUier A braham
undoubtedly re
ferred when he
got off the fa
mous bit or phi
losophy, "You
can fool all of
the people tome
of Uie time, etc.,
etc. otr.
The misfortunes of the day are hke the
premonlUons of fctieezeg. STou know they
are coming, but you can't prevent their
arrival, so It is much better to Miecze
at once, even If your mouth Is full of
turtle soup, than to fight against the in
evitable. It Is better even to take in
the bundle on Uie doorstep than to kick
Ef 55
Vtr
JEm)
Some Old and New Jokes Suggested
The Times for Next Wednesday.
Of Course the Small Boys' WeMried and Proven Schemes Wil
Hold Sway, hut There Is a Chance to Extend Them
into Municipal and National Life
TH SUMS
uoke
by
v d y
f art" and 'Teller." havinsr done -which ha
strode oat of the room. leaviojr the second
fiddle- to play out the score.
It will probably be a bad d7 for king
makers, ho wevcrgooditniay be rorpotitical
fctol makers. In a quiet, coay room In a
Philadelphia hotel there are gathered
together the elect of the Warwlcka
of this day and generation, fore
most among whom are Piatt, Quay and
C I ar krer
"V.
fffj VfLLET vairR
STRlFHi iu v
rti r SL. x pA.
.,mn jr.r.
iA the o rryki ittL -T Ak
Some Ancient and Honorable April Fool Jokes.
Uie little stranger Into the street. There
may be millions awaiting the long-lost
heir before jou die.
The compliments of the season are firstly
due to Uie three destinies of "Washington.
Messrs. Koss, Truesdell and Poweil. Tliej
will do a land-office business on April
Fools' I)a They will be bitting at a Uel
shazzar's feast, and lo' there appears on
Uie wall a strange bcroll in the Kalorama
dialect.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85066387/1899-04-02/ed-1/?sp=11&amp;q=april+fool+pranks</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>Curtain.
April dawned bright and beaming and
kept merry throughout its. first day
blithely warbling between laughs, "Al!
fools look alike to me."
In spite of the fin de siecle pessimist
and his prophecy that All Fool's day was
a landmark of the past, the jester was
out In splendid form and landed gudgeons
galore.
The fun began early and lasted late.
A very few new jokes were perpetrated
and all the old ones revived, while the
usual good humor of both jester and vic
tim prevailed during the entire day. The
email boy was not so much in evidence
;is in previous years. Thoughts of Easter
eggs on the morrow, coupled with the ar
duous duties of trying on new suits and
boots and hats, drove for once all
thoughts of mischief from the mind of
the budding lords of creation. The offi
cials at the Morgue were the first to fall
victims to the merriment- of the day.
When the day was but a half hour old
—at 12:30 a. m.— a telephone call, pre
sumably coming from the Receiving Hos
pital, summoned a Deputy Coroner to take
charge of a body at the Hobson House.
"Hurry-up wagon" and Deputy went
quickly to the place, only to find that
April had dawned and that some one un
known wa? taking liberties with dignified
city officials.
In fact, the Morgue, or. rather, the
Morgue's telephone, was the greatest fcuf
fen-r during the day. The bell rang un-
-ceasingly from early morning until mid
i night and all sorts of messages were
voiced- over the line. Heartless wretches
also employes this method of fooling un
suspecting friends.
Tiner-aling-iing.
"Hello! Well—"
"Oh. la that you. Mary? This is Jim.
Say Mr. Wilson wants to speak with you.
Call him up— No. 1947."
•'Hfllo. No. 1947! Ts this Mr. Wilson?"
"No: this is the Morgue."
A bang— that's Mary's telephone— a
enwe— that is the Morgue.
While people were having fun at the
expense of the city the' city was enjoying
Its own pet little April fool joke—repeat
ing the prank over and over a^aln and
hailing each new victim with shouts of
applause and the shrill tooting of horny.
At the junction of Market. Kearny. and
Third streets at regular intervals a box,
neatly packed and stamped, as though
rc-ady for mailing, would glare the guile
less pedestrian straight in the face. Many
a man, woman and child, representing all
sorts and conditions of society, stooped
to pick up the innocent-appearing box.
None got any farther than the attempt.
The shouts of the crowd, many of them
previous victims, scared the parcel-picker
off, and he hastily lost himself in the
throng and waited in his turn for some
one to laugh at.
It was both a costly and hair-raising
April fool experience that Walter Mosier
had. Mosier. a young man possessed with
an ambition to learn dentistry, is em
ployed by Dr. Perkins, a Sixth-street den
tist. Walter's bogs occasionally allows
him to putter around the molars of his
customers who are out of funds.
One of thes? occasions arose Friday and
Mosier was delegated to perform the
charity service. The, victim was a boy
about 12 years of age. He was suffering
from an ulcerated tooth, and Mosier de
cided that the nerve must be killed, so
forthwith he filled the cavity in the
troublesome tooth with enough arsenic
to kill a horse and sent the unfortunate
youth home happy.
When Dr. Perkins came in Mosier, with
the dignity of a full-fledged dentist, told
his employer of his charity work. Then
Dr. Perkins thought of April fool.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85066387/1900-04-01/ed-1/?sp=4&amp;q=april+fool+pranks</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>Concerning the origin of the name and custom of All fool's day
contributed more to the extermination of
the heathen religion and its priests than
all the collateral aids of fire and sword,
though they were also freely employed.
The continuance of customs— especially
droll ones, which suit the gross taste of
the masses— after the original cause of
them has been removed. Is a very common
occurence. and by many antiquaries It is
firmly believed that "fooling" people on
the Ist of April is simply a perpetuation
of the annual public ridiculing of the old
Druid's and their superstitions.
Still another oripin. of a semi-religious
character, 13 thus claimed for April Fools'
day In a quaint old book of folk-lore
called "Father Time's Flyghtes." pub
lished in London In 1659. "numerous
Jewish Origin of the Custom of Making
Fools on the First of April. This is said
to have begun from "ye mistake of Noah
sending ye dove out before ye water had
abated, on ye first day of ye month which
among ye Hebrews answers to our first
of April, and to perpetrate ye memory of
this deliverance it was thought proper
whoever forgot so remarkable a circum
stance to punish them by sending them
upon some fool's errand similar to- the
Ineffectual message upon which ye bird
was sent by ye patriarch."
The French associate with the first of
April precisely the same Ideas as do Enr
llsh speaking nations, but the person Im
posed upon, whom we call an April FcJ*.
they style an April Fl3h or Polsson d' -v
ril. In the "Etymology of French pro
verbs," a most curious and delightful
work published In 1356. Billlngton I the
author, gives the following expiation
of the origin of April Fool customs "The
word poisson is corrupted throtffn the
Ignorance of the people from pasr'on. and
length of time has almost totall- defaced
the original intention, which w^ as fol
lows: That as the Passion of c-n* Saviour
took place about this time o'the year,
and as the Jews sent Chris*; backward
and forward to mock and't->rment him.
1. c., from Annns to Caiaph?*». from Caia
phas to Pilate, from Pilate Herod and
from Herod back to Pilate, this ridiculous
or rather Impious custorrAook Its rise
from thence, by which we send about
from one place to anoO«r such persona
aa we think proper subjects of our ridi
cule."
But It Is not only thrjU&hout Great Brit
ain, France and our/own country that
fools are made on U« nrst day of April.
The custom 1- elabrratfly observed
throughout Sweden, aid In Germany an
April fool la called elnen zam April
shlcken." The same custom haa also been
observed in India fr>m time immemorial.
Late in March of hold a great celetratton which they call
the Hull festival, of which the last day
is the greatest aid most general holiday.
During the con.nuance of the Hull, one
of its chief dl^rsions is to send people
on errands ar^ expeditions that are to
end In disapr^ ntment anat the expend of the person sent.
But the cistom of making April fools
has-been traced back to an antiquity even
greater t!** n that of the Hull festival of.
the Hind 9 Tne ancient Persians wer»
accustorr«vernal rruinox. which may occur as early
as ila-^n 22 or as late as April 23. with
elaborv*the Utter the chief was the making of
fool- precisely as we are accustomed to
mate them on April Fools* day.
jjp a quaint volume of poem.l bearing
tH title, "Verses On Several Occasions."
i,.id published In London. 1752, April Foola'
.ay is thus alluded to:
Now April morn b!*r Folly's throas exalts:
Now Dobb calls Nell and lauebs because ah*
halts.
"While Nel! meets Tom and Bays his tall la
loose,
Then laughs In turn and caJTa poor Thoma
"Goose."
In England, from earliest times, th»
ridiculous errands upon which the victim
of an April fool Joke sent have been
called "sleeveless errands." but the origin
and true significance of this term ar»
completely buried in oblivion and no an
tiquary has yet been able to unearth
them.The service was very simple about the
sort of thine I should have found In
most Methodist or Congregational meet
ing-houses In an American villas*. Ther»
was a long prayer, a long: sermon, a hymn
or two. a chapter from the Book «f
4
period of eight days. April 1 Is the
octave of March 25, and the last day
of a festival octavo was always marked
by the greatest abandon and festivity.
At the New Year season especially all
sorts of wild, mirthful pranks were In
dulged In, and of these It is believed that
our April fool usages were a part.
Origins of a religious nature have been
boldly claimed for April Fools' day by
many writers. An old English antiquary,
writing In 1753. states that the custom of
imposing upon and ridiculing people on
the Ist of April may have an allusion to
the mockery of the Savior of the world
by the Jews. Something like that which
we call making April fools Is practiced
also abroad in Catholic countries on In
nocents' day, on which occasion people
run through all the rooms, making a pre
tended search in and under the beds. In
memory, I believe, of the search made by
Herod for the discovery and the destruc
tion of the child Jesus and of his having
been imposed upon and deceived by the
wise men, who, contrary to his orders
and expectation, "returned to their own
country another way."
When the early Britons were Induced to
forsake' their Druidical priests and Idols
and to embrace Christianity, It was their
custom" for many years after to annually
hold in their churches at the commence
ment of April a great festival, resem
bling the Roman Saturnalia, at which
they indulged in a thousand ridiculous
and indecent ceremonies, gambols and
dancing grotesquely to ludicrous anthems.
These singular observances referred to the
exploded pretensions of the Druids, whom
this festival was designed to hold up to
scorn and derision. That there Is no more
effective weapon than ridicule was again
proved In this case, for this feast of fools
""Whence proceeds the custom of making
April fools? Answer: From a memorable
transaction happening between the
Romans and the Sabine.3, mentioned by
Dionysius. Which was thus: The Romans,
about the Infancy of their city, wanting
wives, and finding they could not obtain
the neighboring women by their peaceable
addresses, resolved to make use of strata
gem, and accordingly Romulus instituted
certain games to be performed in the be
ginning of April (according to the Roman
calendar) in honor of Neptune. Upon no
tice thereof the bordqring Inhabitants,
with their whole families, flocked to Rome
to see this mighty celebration, whereupon
the Romans seized a number of the Sablna
virgins and ravished them, which imposi
tion, we suppose, may be the foundation
of this foolish custom." This most absurd
and wholly unjustifiable account of the
origin of making April fools is thus ridi
culed by a poet of the time:
Ye witty tiparks who makes pretense
To answer questions with good sense.
How cornea.it that your monthly Phoebus
Is made a fool by Dionysius?
For had the Sablnen, as they -came,
D-partpd with their, vlrirln fame.
The Romans had been Jtyled dull tools,
"And they, poor Rlrls. been April Fools.
Therefore. If this be" n't out of season,
Pray, think and give a better reason.
Some old folk-writers claim that our
April Fool customs are attributable to the
fact that the year formerly began, as to
come purposes and in some respects, on
the 25th of March, which was supposed
?o be the day of Our Lord's incarnation.
At that time' it was customary for all
festivals to continue for an octave, or
(Copyright and nil rights reserved.)
"The first of April lome do say.
TVoa «et apart for All Fools' Day;
But why the people call It «o.
Nor I nor they therr.reUes do know."
Thus an old English poet sings truly,
for It would be a hard matter to find any
one who can give an accurate and correct
account of how the Ist of April came to
be known as All Fools' day and of the ori
gin of the custom pertaining to It of then
_ trying to make fools
W\ of people generally
Sf in every conceivable
tjrfjf V^ WS&JS"'"^ manner. In old
books of folklore al-
most innumerable
r I jo^w statements are made
Bf &a concerning the or-
B y igin of both name
it and custom, all dlf
ferlng as widely as
the poles and bear
ing not the slightest
Wlatlon to each other.
A learned antiquary, writing in 1599,
claims that our April Fools' day Is but a
continuation of the Qulrinalla, or feast of
fools, bf the ancient Romans. In- "The
British Apollo." a most ingenious work
published !n 17C8. I find the following:</text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84028140/1902-04-01/ed-1/?sp=3&amp;q=april+fool+pranks</id>
        <rel>0</rel>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85066387/1911-04-02/ed-1/?sp=1&amp;q=april+fools+pranks</id>
        <rel>0</rel>
        <text></text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn89066313/1915-04-01/ed-1/?sp=1&amp;q=april+foolls+prank</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>THE CALENDAR
April 7. Easter holidays end
Wednes-
in v.
April 8. University assembly at 7:15
o clock. Oreon E. Scott of St Louis will
deliver an Illustrated lecture on South
America.
April 11. Y. M. C. A. twenty-fifth anni
versary celebration. Dr. Frank Burt of
'lilencn nlll be me of the speakers.
April 13. Dr. J. Boss Stevenson, presi
dent of Princeton Theological Seminary,
will speak at the University assembly at 2
o clock.
April 15. Mme. Schnninnii Ilruilc concert
In University Auditorium, i'nl .Mil Alpha
wrlei.
April 10. Virgil's Aeneld, to be given by
Senior Latin Class of Columbia High
School In Christian College Auditorium.
.April 23. Debate with the University of
Kansas Debating Team In the University
Auditorium at 8 o'clock.
April 23. Farmers' County Fair by stu
dents, College of Agriculture.
Slav L High School Day. Athletic meet
and Literary contest.
Slay 3-7. Journalism Week. Popular
lectures. University Auditorium each even
ing. MARCH BREAKS OLD RECORD
Last Month Third Coldest ia Tweaty
SIx Years.
The month just passed was the
third coldest March in the last twenty
six years, according to the local
Weather Bureau. In 1906 and 1912
the average temperature was slight
ly lower than for last month. The
emperature was 6 degrees below the
March normal.
There were no extremely cold days
In March, 1915, however. The low
average was due to the fact that there
were no warm days, as is usually the
case. Several times before the tem
perature on a day in March has been
below zero, while the lowest last
month was 22. Never before, however,
has the maximum temperature for any
March day been as low as it was this
month, 63 degrees.
About a third of the usual precipita
tion fell last month. The heavy snow
on March 4 was responsible for most
of the precipitation. Nevertheless,
there were only two clear days in the
entire month.
GLEE CLUB HAS EASTER TRIP
Six Towns and Cities Will Be Visited
Before Return April 8.
The University of Missouri Glee
and Mandolin Clubs left today for
their Easter concert tour of the state.
The first concert will be given tomor
row night In Macon. Klrksvllle,
Brookfleld, Savannah, Chllllcothe and
Kansas City will be visited by the
clubs before their return to Columbia
on April 8.
The first home concert of the reor
ganized clubs will be given in the
University Auditorium on Friday
night April 9. An admission will be
charged and tickets for the concert
will be placed on sale Wednesday.
The clubs will be the guests of the
alumni of the towns in which con
certs are given.. The Elks' Club of
Klrksvllle will give a dance after the
concert there and the Kansas City
alumni are planning a recepUon for
them.
CHARGE TWO WITH BURGLARY
Police Believe Joel Bradford, Jr., and
Harry Flte Bobbed Grocery Stores.
Joel Bradford, Jr., and Harry Fite
are being held by the police, charged
with robbing Van Horn's and Weir's
grocery stores on the night of Febru
ard 26. They were arrested today.
Bradford was arrainged on two
counts before Justice Kurtz this
morning and pleaded not guilty. His
hearing was set for April 8.
The boys are about 20 years old.
The police say that Fite, who has
served a term In the reform school,
confesses to robbing the stores and
Implicated Bradford. Bradford says
he had nothing to do with the rob
beries. H.U.Gradaate,Now Instructor, YlsKs.
Harvey Howell, a graduate of the
College of Agriculture, was visiting
friends In Columbia Monday. Mr.
Howell is now Instructor of dairy
husbandry In the University, of
Georgia.
SPECIAL EASTER
SERVICESPLAHNED
All Columbia Churches Are
Arranging Extra Programs
for Day of Gladness.
MUSIC
FEATURE
Holy Communions Will Be
Served, New Members Re
ceived and Baptized.
Easter Sunday will be celebrated
by Columbia churches with special
services. Nearly all the religious or
ganizations have arranged something
extra in the way of a program for this
day. The pastors will deliver special
sermons, the. choirs will give extra
musical programs, and new members
will be received into the churches.
At the Christian Church the Rev.
Madison A. Hart will preach Sunday
morning at 10:45 o'clock on "The
Resurrection and the New Gladness."
The choir, in charge of Miss Myrtle
Parker, will give a special program
at this service. Following the regular
Sunday School hour and preceedlng
the morning sermon, a short program
will be given by some of the pupils
In the primary and junior 'departments
of the Sunday School. The Reverend
Hart will also talk at the regular
evening services at th.Is church.
The Holy Sacrament and the Lord's
Supper will be served at the Broad
way Methodist Church Sunday morn
ing. New members will be received
and baptized. A special musical pro
gram will be given in addition to this.
At the evening services the Kev. A.
C. Johnson, presiding elder, of the
Fayette district, will preach.
Special services will a'so be given
Sunday morning at the Baptist and
the Presbyterian Churches. At the
former the Rev. T. W. Young will
preach at 10:45 o'clock on "The Call
of the Resurrection." New members
will be received and special musical
programs will be given, at both these
churches.
There will be three services at Cal
vary Episcopal Church Easter. At
7:30 a. m. there will be the Easter
celebration of the Holy Communion
and the singing of Easter hymns. At
10:30 o'clock In the morning there
will be the Easter Festival services,
with choral accompaniment and a ser
mon by the Rev. F. J. Bate on "The
Choice of the Three Ifs." The Knights
Templar and the Masons will attend
this service In a body. The choir will
sing anthems. At 4:30 there will be
Evening Prayer and a short address.
This service Is especially for chil
dren. The Lenten Mite boxes will be
gathered at this service.
DEAN LOEB TO WED APRIL 6
Miss -Carrie Lengrsfield of New Orleans
Will Be Bride of Faculty Head.
Dr. Isldor Loeb, dean of the Univer
sity faculty, left this afternoon for
New Orleans, where he will be mar
ried April 6 to Miss Carrie Lengsfield.
The wedding will be a family affair at
the 'home of the bride at 1540 Felicity
street, New Orleans. Dean Loeb and
his bride will come to Columbia about
the middle of April and will make their
home at 408 South Ninth street until
next falL
Members of Dean Loeb's family who
will go to New Orleans for the wed
ding are: Dr. and Mrs. H. W. Loeb,
Miss Irene Loeb, Mr. and Mrs. Alex
Loeb, Mr. and Mrs. Max J. Mayer, all
of St Louis; Mrs. Herman Loeb, Rich
Hill, and Mr. and Mrs. Leon Loeb,
Wichita Falls, Tex.
FULTON CAS DAMAGED HERE
Automobile of Dr. H. C Ward la Col
llsioa ob Broadway.
In a collision at Ninth street and
Broadway last night the car of Dr. H.
C. Ward of Fulton was damaged about
$50. The radiator was torn off and the
fan and one of the springs were
broken.
Doctor Ward was going west on
Broadway when a car which E. C.
Clinkscales says belongs to Benjamin
M. Payne and was driven by Mr. Payne
or a negro chauffeur from the Clink
scales Garage, turned the corner on to
Broadway from Ninth, on the left hand
side.
License Issied to Wilton Ceaple.
A license to marry was Issued today
to Elbert Smith, 21 years old, and
Larlne Nichols, 18 years old. Both are
from Wilton, Mo.
Famers Fair Posters DIstrflwteA.
Posters advertising the Farmers'
Fair were distributed this morning to
all agricultural students going home
for the Easter holidays.</text>
      </result>
    </results>
  </topic>
  <topic>
    <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-boston-subway/</id>
    <results>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84024441/1897-03-04/ed-1/?sp=5&amp;q=Boston+Dead+dead+explosion+flame+gas+Gas+Subway</id>
        <rel>0</rel>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030214/1897-09-19/ed-1/?sp=32&amp;q=BOSTON+Boston+BOSTONS+SUBWAY+subway</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>the
subway is broaden? I A high Air? fenc? runa
lengthwise In the middle, irallng the two
noi thboui -1 tr u from the tw?i soul hi un I.
The tra- lu of e.i., t, p.ur are Ivided i rial n
gineers call an "island platform." saj feel
wide, and 300 or IfSJ feel long. Ace? i.m tie
had to on? platform from the ??(her onlj b) pro
Ing down a low flight of ita ai i through a
narrow bul brightly Illuminated pas age undei
n- ath, oi i going up i the street and rosslng
iv? r.
The cara v. hi, h run Ihn ugh the tunnel ar- oi
("..i irj li lej cars, but, iik.- many which tra-.
i other rout? In t!:-- i ty, th? y are all con?
trolled by one ror|ioratliin, Ihe West Knd Street
Hallway Company, to which, by the way, the
subwaj la- lieen leased by th? Tran t Commis
i neri 'iii fact partially explains some of the
pri au ?i taken al the stations. Then one
buys a ii ki t In lure h >a riling i.u or Hing a,
rhan? e to do o, are) thi ndui lor on I h? car col
lecta Ihe Ll? kets, Kill fn m th? i tatlon i lat
Is effected Ihrouul lun les, wbi< b a.. >w
a person to pa In onlj ?in dh i ion.
in. id, easy stall rid d n n from Ih I reel
r? the und und statloi 'i i
more than thirty Btej In a (light Th ai
two flights for He northbound tracks, ind two
f ?r the Bouthl ?ui I The h ud of a li
i.; in loa d by a neat oni tory, gla
granite b ill lin Glazed white i?i i. i< and i I? lit)
?,f whit.- paint Impart to ihe station interlora
a fresh and the r> appearance. At present t?..-
BOSTON'S NEW SUBWAY INCLINE IN THE PUBLIC GARDEN.
?nly stations in use underground are at the cor
ner of Boylston and Tremont sts. ami at Park-st
A temporary loop at the latter point permits
the northbound cars to return without switch?
ing. When the subway is completed, however.
there uiii i.ther stations at Si o lay Square,
Adams Square and Hay market Square.
miy an engineer can begin to understand
th.- difficulties of an undertaking lik?- this
Count leas sewers, a ater-plpcs, gasplp? s and tele
phon? -Air.- conduits have been laid close to the
route, and Bom of ih.s,- have been bared dur?
ing the prigresa of the necessary excavation.
When ihelr position was at a higher level than
the r..of ,,f the future subway it was not neces?
sary to do ne re than lo protect them carefully
f.r the lime. Bui if the) were lower than the
roof, and higher than the Boor, the situation
was root, serious. Two great water mains, one
thirty Inches In diameter and the other forty
BOSTONS NEW SUBWAY FOUR-TRACK SUBWAY UNDER TRKMONT-ST.
Inches across, ?ere encountered at that very in
invenlent level, It became necessary to con
utru t siphons, bending down under the subway
and up agiln on the other Bide, in order to ad
ju-t these conflicts of Interest. Kor the happy
solution of all th.-:- difficulties great credit is
,'-j to th? t'ity Commission Intrusted with the
work, to their 'hlef ngli.r, and, in some meas?
ure, t. the engine, rs of the West End Company,
An Incidental l j: I mi orlant f. ature of tlie
plan of construction Is the avoidance of grade
i rossinirs. In the four-track passageway the
Iloylston-st. ears have the two inside tracks,
and the Tremont-st and Bhawmut-ave. ears use
the two outer ones in common. Accordingly,
at th" southeastern corner of the Common, the
westernmost track (southnound) is carried down
Under the two central ones, by a special one
track tunrnl which soon emerges With another
one-track tunnel carrying th>- up-track. At a
point still further south a similar plan Is pur
sued in th.- separating of the Bhawmut-ave. and
Tremont-st. cars
Tie- cipa. Ity of the subway is ninety cars
per mit,ute. Inasmui h as th" facilities thus af?
forded :ir.- Buppli mentary to th.me already af
forded on Tremont-st., and an- not a substitute
for the latter, a distinct increase In the number
of punes, as well as freedom from blockades,
bas been secured.
RJtlUYBRAVIVO POSTAI* CARDS.
i From The Boston Transcript.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84024441/1897-03-04/ed-1/?sp=5&amp;q=Boston+Dead+dead+explosion+flame+gas+Gas+Subway</id>
        <rel>0</rel>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn95079490/1897-10-23/ed-1/?sp=7&q=BOSTON+SUBWAY</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>THE BOSTON SUBWAY
SATISFACTORY SOLUTION OF THE
STREET CAR PROBLEM.
Contention of Trafllc In tli? Iluny Streets
of the Uub Relieved by Underground
Trolley Lines?Tunnels Tlmt Am Light,
Clean uud Attractive.
It is now possible to cross Tromont
street, Boston, at any point opposite tho
Common and at any time of day without
loss of life or limb. Tho new subway has
brought about tho change.
It 1 s an old tradition that tho fathers of
Boston, when thoy laid out tho city, let
the. streets follow the winding cow paths.
At any rate, the streets ius thoy exist today
urc very crooked and must of them aro
very narrow. This was all right in Revo?
lutionary times, but when the city grow
miles beyond tho Common und spread it?
self out to tho south and west; when busi?
ness centered itself along tbu lower ends
of Washington and Trentont streets, and
when dozens of street car tracks usurped
tho narrow roadways, then the Bostonlans
wished their ancestors bud not stuck so
closely to the cow paths.
Probably no other city on the continent,
was ever so badly allllctcd with a conges?
tion of trnllic as tho Hub haslieon for
many yea: Some of tho most important
street ear linen skirt tho south and east,
cornets ol the Common on Boylston mid
Tremont streets. When I he chango was
made hum hoc. epov.vr to trolley, matters
grew worse. Then tho poles and the tan?
gle of overhead wires made that historic.
breathing spot look liko a pieco of dingy,
green billiard cloth which had become fray?
ed and tuttered around the edges. So after
much wrangling in tho legislature and
courts it w;ls decided tu build the subway
and put the trolley cars underground.
A large portion of the work bus already
lieen accomplished and Boston is delight?
ed with the result. The first thing a Hus?
ton man asks a visitor from Now York,
Chicago or elsewhere is:
"Been through tho subway yet'/ Let's
see?you huven't one in your place, have
you?"
It is, in fact, a triumph of engineering
anil well worth a visit. Then! arc throe
open cut.s where tho trolley curs enter the
subway. One Is out on Tremont street
whore Shawmut avenue comes in. Hero
the tracks from each of those jmorough
fares dive into the tunnel. Another is In
the Public gardens, where the cars com?
ing down Boylston street take tho under?
ground tlip. The third is at tho northerly
end of the subway, just beyond-Hay mar?
ket square and in front of the new Union
terminal railroad station into which the
Fitchburg, Hoston und Maine, Eastern
und other roads run. Theru is u. loop hern
DOSTON'S NEW SUBWAY INCLINE IN THE Plin
LIC ns most of the t rolley lines inako it their
terminus, and, the subway being four
tracked, they disgorge their passengers
and take the back track up town.
Including the inclines or open onto, tho
subway has a total length of 1 miles and
will contain about live miles of track. At
present the branch down Boylston street
along the Common side and the main line
down Tremont to Park street are in oper?
ation. The Shawmut avenue branch and
tho northerly end of the main lino will be
finished within the next eight months.
Ground was broken for the subway in
April, 18115. The sum appropriated was
$7,ii(?0,000 and, wonderful to relate, tho
transit commissioners say that it is proba?
ble the cost will bo about $1,000,000 less
than that sum.
No groat difficulties have been encoun?
tered thus far in digging this big liplo In
the ground. Of course there were count?
less sewers, water pipes, gas pipes, electric
wire conduits and the like und some -III
inch water mains at an inconvenient level
proved rather hnrxl to handle, but n? un?
expected conditions arose to delay tho
work. The main trunk of the subway
runs under the wide walk or mall on tho
east side of the Common, anil when the
excavations were being made the bones of
hundreds of old Puritans were disturbed.
This raised a bowl of righteous Indigna?
tion,and the sncredness of the long forgot
burying ground was harped upon for
weeks. Hut the commissioners quieted
the reverent patriots by collecting nil tho
bones and roiuterrlng them in the holy
ground of the Common, with a nice monu?
ment to mark the spot.
The tleepest jioint of tho subway is on
Boylston street, where the south bound
t racks are laid lit) feet lielow the surface,
but the average depth is 14 feet. The tun?
nel itself is a giant bore with ribs of steel
mid casings! of cement, asphalt, concrete
and masonry. The roof is a series of
arches und the floor Is concave, with
drains at the bottom. As tho drnins are
below the level of the sewers, jilts have
been established at Intervals, and when
thev are filled with water automatic elec?
trical pumps are started, which empty
them Into tho sewers above.
Perhaps yon imagine that Boston's sub?
way is a tlark, damp, ill smelling place. It
is nothing of the sort. The entrances to
the stations aro handsome structures of
stone, with glass roofs. The only fault, to
be found with them is that thev remind
cs?blc. It makes food shortened
it i3 uahcaltb.ru! and filled with
icd by every medical r.::d culi- B
1
vegetable oil is nutritive, digest-
i
coil. Itisnu
:d with or fried
armful results.
md yoll^w tins,with
u((nM-/ililii( urc.il??
way. lladounlyby
1 PAN Y,
Montreal. ^?-?n?? _^ff* fa
you or an olo Urccinn tomi)?ft" least that
is what I thought of the first time I saw
one. Put then you go down an easy (light
of wide stone steps to n cheerful, brilliant?
ly lighted station. Everything Isdazzllug
ly white. The bricks lining the entrance
art? of glazed white porcelain, the mason?
ry arches are painted white and the iron
pillars and supports arc covered with im?
maculate white; enamel. Incandescent and
are lights Hash everywhere, and the vista
nhead through tho stretches of the subway
is far from u dingy one. It. Is about tho
cleanest und neatest holu In tho ground in
existence and no doubt will be kept so.
Already lifo tralllo on Tromont and Duyl
ston streets has been much decreased, ami
when tl;e subway is fully completed Bos?
ton foil: may get about their town with
comparative ease und safety.
ALKKKD U. ROWLEY</text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030272/1897-12-15/ed-1/?sp=3&amp;q=BOSTON+Boston+SUBWAY+subway</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>'BOSTON'S UNUSED SUBWAY.
ft) H' VMDBnOltOVSD TBAXBITA TAILURE
j jjv oxvU x. rjtA otice.
Ij aYeople Reniie ta L'se It. Jot as Thfir Wonld
.1' the Hot la tbo Cronna Transit rropwed
J'v fbr Wew .rk Only Keren Per Cent, ef the
M Total Tronic Credited ta the flatmar The
j rreniable rnney TraDI o Lost to It Entirely
Jf Vat tba Condlllem Are nl Farorablr
BbS. Beaten Want, an Klevatrd nallraad Hon,
'sflf "H Before any farther attempt la mado to com'
i V Bait tbli eltr to the building of the proposed
jH underground system of rapid tranalt it would
H be well for every ono Interested to learn somo-
ll thing of the experience which Boston Is now
I lusTlng with Its subway. Boston's subway Is
li'H New York's proposed underground railroad In
L S miniature, excopt that It was constructed for
I H the use of the trolley car lines Instead of being
I V equipped with cars, motors, and power of Its
I H own, and mnnlnir two sets of trains one express
tf( I and one local.
The Boston subway short. That part now
jkVM tense Is less than ft mile In length, and the
KS farts which are under construction or proposed
R M Would add only about another mile to the tun
Hk wr Bet, There lr, perhaps, no finer specimen of
Jl&B passenger tunnel work any whero In the world,
aBfYS n ls doubtful -f anymore perfect tunnel
HtjH could Deconstructed.
B9p The tunnel runs under Tremont street, and
HHk Its extensions are to go under Cornhlll, Han
JJ. oxer street, and Washington streot, passing
i right through the denso business and shopping
districts, and thus securing every advantage
I that a road might have If It ran through Broad-
jf Tray, Fourteenth street and Twenty-third street,
i and part of Sixth avenue. And yet. In the face
j ef all these advantages, three months' experi
ence has shown that the Boston subway is not
popular, that people will not go Into It ex-
cept when they have to, and that the subway Is
lv a failure, save so far as It was a necosslty to re-
i'i Have the congestion of traffic on the street.
V XEED OF TUB BUDWAT.
A Bostonlans are proud of the subway. They
ri take strangers to see It, just as they take them
h to see Bunker IIIll Monument; make them ride
vM the length of It back and forth, and call alien
s' I tlon to all its fine foatures and then they keep
I away from it themsolves. Just as thoydofrom
if the monument. That this result ls of tntorest
I V to New Yorkers there can be no doubt. Tho
building of tbo subway growoutof a publloneed
Tfhloh was as absolute and pressing as the need
v ef this city for some addition to Its trafllo
in. facilities.
Hien, about ten years ago. the West End
oet Railway Company began to transform tho
horso car lines of Boston Into electric trot
lines the narrow streets In tho heart of
iton were already choked with tho dally rush
vehicles. Boston has to-day tho most ex
stve and comprehensive electrlo car system
the world. The added cars which wero re
red for tho now service fairly filled
i streets of the little central city
ere they were all concentrated. These
lines eorvo a suburban population of
trly a million persons, and it is possible to
;e a car for any part of the territory covered
.hoot going more thai a quarter of a mllo In
i city. Under a special act of the Lcglsla
e the Boston Transit Commission was ap
nted to devise a suitable means to relieve the
Station.
THE OrERATIVB COWTnAOT.
fader this commission tho subway wns
nned and is being built. Tho city of Boston
s for it and leases it to tho West End Street
llway Company for twenty years at an an
il rental which is not to be less than 4Ts per
it. upon the net cost of the tunnel, or more
,n .Ts per cent, upon tho sum of $7,000,000,
he tunnol should cost so much, and tho com
ly agrees to pay. in llou of interest, a toll of
nts for each car that passes through the
way. In caso the aggregate of tolls should
:eed the interest charges. The railroad com
ly cares for it, lights it, ventilates it, ana
ips It free from wator. i
fork was bosun on the subway on March 28,
13, and on Sept. 1 of this rear the first scc
o was put Into use.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn82016413/1901-07-24/ed-1/?sp=6&amp;q=Boston+subway</id>
        <rel>0</rel>
        <text>There Is a rumor that the bean-cat-,
Ing, blue-blooded Boston dames have
mounted a new bobby. They rldo
astride. Not the bobby, but the horse.
They think this Is a good time to be
gin, says the New York Sun. Since
the Boston subway uus completed, a
large part of the population spends Its
time underground, riding back and
forth through the tunnel and exclaim
ing: "Wo did It!
This has Increased the above-ground
Inhabitants to so small a number that
It's a good time to oercomo public
opinion, because there's so little of It
to overcome. Consequently thd Boston
women refeired to t:nn seized the
chance to establish the new fad In rid
ing. They Know that by the tlmo the
people get tired ut looking nt their hole
In the ground, bloomers will nave be
come a pait of thfl Boston eieed of B's.
Its growing. Already It Includes Bos
ton bens, Boston bays, Boston blue
blood and Boston has bleus,
Within a few wck& the same rumor
has broken out nearer home. Newspa
per paragraphs have declared that New
York women, too, are going to aban
don the side puddle, aud takn to di
vided skirts. Doctors uho have been
consulted sigh and Bay they only wish
tuc rumor would come true. They do
what they tan to push It along. They
prescribe tiding nstilde, and say It Is.
tho only healthful and safe way for
anybody to tide. But tbij tity that
It'R ono of the presctltplons which New
iork women u.iu o tar declined to
take.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030214/1903-06-21/ed-1/?sp=42&amp;q=BOSTON+subway</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>THE MARCH OF IMPROVEMENT IS FAST OBLITERATING MANY OF BOSTONS MOST FAMOUS OLD LANDMARKS
OLD STATIC HOUSE, BOSTON.
To be transformed Into a tunnel station for the subway
BOSTON IMPROVEMENTS.
Historic Landmarks and Crooked
Streets Disappearing.
Boston, June 20.— Within three years the
crooks and turnings and devious wanderings of
Boston's most honored highways and byways
will be nothing more than a memory of the past,
and many of her ancient landmarks will be
wiped out or so altered as to be unrecognizable
to the oldest inhabitant. Slowly and surely the
ancient thoroughfares are being widened,
straightened and bent into the rulerlike lines oC
i rosscut New- York. Philadelphia and Chicago.
Boston is undergoing a transformation below
arid aloft that would cause Benjamin Franklin.
John Hancock, "Warren and Paul Revere *.o rub
their eyes and stare in amazement. Million dol
lar buildings by the dozen, elevated roads, tun
nels and streetcar lines beneath the streets and
under the harbor, swamps and mud Hats filled
for piers and excavated for docks that ac
':;iinodate giant steamers these are the things
they would see.
Along State-st., beneath the spot where the
Boston Massacre occurred, and beneath the his
toric old State House, a tunnel is eating its way
from under the harbor to Scollay Square to con
nect with the present subway by means of
(lights of stairs and elevators, and thence out
side to the busy world. The old Slat- House
itself is to be transformed into a tunnel station
connecting with a subway line also. The re
modelled building will soon be crowded with
people hurrying back and forth, intent on busi
ness, with never a thought of its old associa
tions. Little do they think, as they hurry past
where tunnel workmen are digsing seventy feet
beneath, of what has happened In that quaint
old edifice. On this site the first State House
was built in 1G57. Destroyed by fire in 1711. it
was rebuilt In 1712, and rebuilt again in 1747,
when destroyed a second time. The building
has been in turn Town House, Courthouse. Prov
ince House, State House and City Hall. <>n the
NEW-YORK TRIBUNE ILLUSTRATED SUPPLEMENT.
PAIIK STREET CHUUCR, "RRIMSTONE CORNER," BOSTONT.
It is to make way for a skyscraper.
first floor in the early days was the merchants*
walk, or exchange.
During the Stamp Act excitement the stamped
clearances were burned in front of its doors.
The British troops were quartered within the
building in 17'J.S, and the Boston Massacre oc
curred about fifty feet away on March 1770.
The next day Samuel Adams stood in the coun
cil chamber and made his successful demand
upon the royal representatives fur the immedi
ate removal of the British troops from Boston.
In this same room Generals Clinton, Howe and
Gage held a council of war just before the bat
tle of Bunker Hill. In 17N'J, at the western end
of the State House, Washington reviewed the
great procession in his honor on the occasion of
his last visit to Boston. Here, also, in lSi>s,
William Lloyd Garrison found refuge from a
mob which had broken up an anti-slavery meet
ing, and threatened his life.
The Park-st. station of the present subway
handles I!7,course of its trolley traffic, but the number of
passengers who will pass through the old State
House station will far exceed this number.
The march "f progress does not stop here,
however. Down Washington-st., to connect with
the tunnel and present subway, will be another
subway, this a double one for elevated trains
after they leave tli" surface at the Broadway
extension. It will pass beneath the Old South
Church, the Old Corner Bookstore and other well
known landmarks. Through the tower of the
»lil South Church, which juts out into Washing
ton-st., it is planned to cut an arcade, in the
g< neral scheme of widening and straightening
Washington-st.</text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84020274/1904-05-08/ed-1/?sp=57&amp;q=New+subway+York</id>
        <rel>0</rel>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn88085947/1904-10-27/ed-1/?sp=1&q=NEW+OPENED+SUBWAY+YORK</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>The Rapid
Transit railroad, the subway, as It
Is popularly known, nnd the most
colossal undertaking of its kind in
the worlds history, whs formally
opened today with imposing cere
saonies. The exercises took place
under the joint auspices of the Inter
borough company and the board of
aldermen. In City Hull park, where
the great downtown terminal is lo
cated and where the first spadeful
of earth was turned, the principal
ceremonies of the day took place
shortly before noon. The park and
citl hall were lavishly decorated.
Bishop Pottter opened the cere
monies with prayer and was followed
by an address by Alexander E. Orr,
president of the rapid transit com
mission, who turned the subway over
to the city. Mayor McClellan accept
ed the tiust, and then turned the road
over to August Belmont, president of
the Interborough company, who also
made a brief address. Archbishop
Farley closed the ceremonies.
At 1 o'clock the first train was
started over the road, operated by
Mayor McClellan in person. Hands
of music were stationed at all the
principal stops along the route. In
cluded among the passengers on the
first train were the city officials, of
ficials of the Interborough company,
a large party of distinguished engi
neers and other invited guests.
Promptly at midnight tonight the
road will be opened to the general
public. That part of the road that
will be operated for the present In-
It is to tight Jeunnot Bros, that
the Spokane Grocers' association has
been Incorporated "to foster a per
manent social feeling" among the
grocers.
The grocers' trust has been making
an illegal tight In using the boycott.
The members knew this and they
knew also that every member of the
trust was liable personally to the
courts for the acts of the organiza
tion.
In order to relieve the Individual
grocers from the fear of being com
pelled to pay damages in ease any
boycotted firm or grocer instituted
suit the trust has been incorporated.
Of the men who are the Incorpor
ators. C F. Blegler runs a trust gro
cery at |MI Second avenue, ft ft.
Andersons trust grocery is at 301
llogan street; P. Nelson offers gro
ceries at trust prices at 01730 Divis
ion street; John Gilford Son have
trust goods for sale ut 1730 liroad
way; Eliza N. t'ory is the secretary
of the association of trust grocers.
It win be noticed that tho big gro
cers arc not showing up in the of
ficial positions of the trust associa
tion. The "little fellows' have been
forced into those dangerous positions.
They will stand personal responsibil
ity, but the big grocers will put up
the money for the trust fights.
As an Incorporated body the trust
grocers nr* not now Individually re
sponslble for the law-breaking meth
ods of the boycott. This is the rea
son the Spokane Grocers' association
was Incorporated.
The Press believes the greedy oc
topus which Is formed to grind still
harder the workingman and his tam
lly should be checked.
W. W. JACOBS, A PLAT
WRIGHT AND HU-
SECOND YEAR. NO. 295. PBICE: ONR CENT.
dudes the whole of the main line
from City Hall park to the Harlem
river on the upper west side. It is
expected to have the entire west side
line opened to- traffic within a month
or so nnd also the east side branch
to the Bronx.
The great subway opened today
consists of It miles of railroad under
the city's teeming streets. The actual
work of construction has taken Just
four years and the cost has exceeded
150.000,000. When the entire system
is completed it will enable one to
travel from the limits of Brooklyn
to the northernmost end of Manhat
tan entirely underground.
A dazzling array of facts and fig
ures tell the story of the building
of the mammoth underground road.
For instance, more than 8,000,000
cubic yards of dirt and rock were
blasted Hnd dug from the streets of
the crowded city. To tear away the
rock voo.ooo pounds of dynamite were
used. Eleven thousand men were em
ployed In the work and of this num
ber several hundred lost their lives
through accidents, premature ex
plosions, cave-Ins und falling rock.
It Is estimated that the road will
carry 115,000,000 passengers a year.
The fare Is 5 cents. When the ex
tension to Brooklyn, under the East
river, has been completed It is esti
mated that the road will carry 200,-
UOO.OOO passt-nxers year.
Express trains will run through
the subway at the rate of a mile a
minute for the benefit of the long
hauls from the Bronx to the busiest
sections of the city below Fourteenth
Englishmen like to laugh as
heartily as their American brothers
when the Joke Is of their kind, and
Jacobs knows how to provide fun i
that is International. He gained his
knowledge of river life and charac
ter on the wharf ut Wapping, where
he spent his leisure hours as a boy.
Mr. Jacobs Is a Londoner born and
bred, and until the last few years
has stuck pretty closely to a city
life. He was educated at private
schools and only live years ago gave
up his appointment in the savings
l»ank department in the general post
office, which he had held since 1883.
lie is 41 years old. but he looks
such a boy, with his clean-shaven
I
face, mm figure end t¥r£si*j»~' tssrt
old ladles In omnibuses still otter
1 hiss ehooolates as to a youth of la,
Mr. Jacobs confesses that he hates to.
work, be put from I
one ceil
street. </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn87060004/1905-01-19/ed-1/?sp=4&amp;q=BOSTON+Boston+SUBWAY+subway</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>ANOTHER BOSTON SUBWAY
Eat Ilpnlon Tunnel Junt Openti
IllliiM Under Itnrbor
Boston the pioneer city of America
In subway construction now boasts a
subway Maid to be the greatest single
boring yet completed under the enter
of a river or harbor It Is tho EnSt
Boston tiinnl extending from tile
zing UA8T JtOSTON TUNNEL
city proper under the harbor to
Maverick square East Boston It Is
the second subway to be opened In
Boston wns begun In 1000 has cost
3000000 and has Just been turned
over to tint Boston EIu rated Rallwny
company for operation It Id about
one ones twofifth miles In length and
has an exterior diameter of nearly
thirty feet thoilgli the thickness of
the walls bring Its Interior diameter
down to about twentyfour feet
The East Boston tunnel nets to n
depth of more than ninety feet below
tho waters of Boston harbor through
n blue day sediment It Is fov the
use of regulntlpn trolley cars which
come to the surface at the suburban
end of tilt passage nnd continue their
Journeys over tliestrce trucks Kven
trashy the tuba Vlll be connected di
rectly with the present Ruiwny In Ba
tons congested dlflUlct</text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84023296/1906-06-09/ed-1/?sp=1&amp;q=bomb+Bomb+Boston+explosions+FIRE+subway</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>Boston A dull, low ronr, llko tho
blast of n chnrge of dynnmlte under
tona of grnnlte, nnd clouda ot black,
Blckenlng smoko belchlng fortli,
threw hundreds of men nnd women
into a panic nnd paralyzed trnfflc ln
the subwny nt the Boylston street
statlon at 5.30 o'clock, Wednesday af-
ternqpn
No one know the trouble. Elevatcd
road employes and offlclals were allke
confused, and fearful of what mlght
come next, fla tho smoko raphlly fllleil
tho stntloim at Boylston and Park
streets, nnd passengers wers rushed
from tlie cars to the surfacc.
Tralnmen nnd statlon pollce at
tempted to call the flrd departmont
and found tho telephones so charged
wlth clectrlclty as to be useless.
Mnny of the women reachlng the
subway by the Boylston street cars
were overcomo by the smoko, falnted,
nnd had to be dragged to the surfnce.
Several becanio hysterlcal and woro
controlled wlth much dimculty, the
danger belng constant of Bomeono
falllng from tho platforms overcome
by tho smoko and becomlng electro
cuted upon the deadly thlrd rall.
Tralnmaster Benjamln wns the flrst
offlclal to reach the Boylston street
statlon and to brlng some sort of or-
der out of tho cliaos. Enterlng the
subway along the llne of the north
bound cars he made hla way some 100
feet to the south of tlie statlon and
found the cause of the trouble.
The feed cables for the thlrd rall,
runnlng between the ralla and en
closed ln four-inch wooden box con
dults, were found grouuded and
throwlng off flashes of electrlclty,
whlch llluminnted the subway for
tnany hundreds of feet. The electrl
clty had jumped to other cables run
nlng parallel, and even charged the
wnlla of the subway. Ten powerful
cables felt the lnftuence of the crosn
nnd were cracklng nnd throwlng off
flames and flashes of llght, threaten
Ing death to any who cnme near.
Tho wooden box condtilt, black and
greasy and very Inflammable, was
burnlng rapldly. A north bound traln
whlch had passed over the spot got
nflro nnd wna inillod bnnk lo Waont
street, hlnzlng flercely underneath.
Tlie terrlfled passengers were hnnied
ntt nt Plpnsnnt Rtreet nnd tlie flro be-
nnivth tho. Kttn"gulshed by'road
employes before serlous damage was
done.
Three persons were hurt, nnd all of
them were on the surface. The nccl
dents whlch caused thelr Injurles were
the dlrect result of the trouble In tbo
subway. The Injured wero all near
the Pleasant street entrance to tho
Biibwny and were hurt by the explo
sions in three mnnholes at tliat polnt.
Tralnmaster Benjamln ordered all
tralns Into statlons, and then the cnr-
rent on the thlrd rall and feed cables
was shut off.
Chlef Mullcn and the flre depart
ment hod been notlfled before tho
power was shut off and entered tho
nubway nt the Boylston street sta
tlon, although there was great danger
for anyone, however famlllar ylth the
subway, to enter ln tlie dense smoke
whlch flllcd every foot of space be
tween the walls.
As Chlef Mullen's men toucbed the
walls thoy felt a shock at once. The
brass nozzle of the chemlcal hose
Ihey carrled became charged, and wlth
electrlclty runnlng up thelr arms the
men hcsltated for a mlnute for orders
from thelr chlef.
rlsk It," shouted Chlef Mull
en, and he dashed Into the smoko
filled subway. Hla men followed close
behlnd, thelr hands on the shoulders
of the men In front. A few darlng
newspaper men brought up the rear.
Half an hour was consumed ln put
llng out the flames whlch had fol
lowed nlong the box condults nearly
300 ynrds.</text>
      </result>
    </results>
  </topic>
  <topic>
    <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-early-electric-cars</id>
    <results>
      <result>
	<id>/</id>
	<rel></rel>
	<text></text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>/</id>
	<rel></rel>
	<text></text>
      </result>
    </results>
  </topic>
</topics>
